https://www.ncpssm.org/privacy/

Privacy - NCPSSM
Skip to content
FacebookTwitterLinkedInInstagram
SearchNewsAbout UsJoinSupport Us
Search for:
Our Issues Social SecurityMedicareMedicaidOlder AmericansCoronavirusWhat We Do Take ActionLetters and Testimony2020Campaigns Hands Off No CutsDon’t Cut Pills Cut ProfitsBoost Social Security NowStop the War on the Working ClassBlogResources Delay and GainAsk UsOur Allies116th CongressPACEleanor’s HopeEqual TimePollsReady to Attire
Search for:
Our Issues Social SecurityMedicareMedicaidOlder AmericansCoronavirusWhat We Do Take ActionLetters and Testimony2020Campaigns Hands Off No CutsDon’t Cut Pills Cut ProfitsBoost Social Security NowStop the War on the Working ClassBlogResources Delay and GainAsk UsOur Allies116th CongressPACEleanor’s HopeEqual TimePollsReady to AtireJoinSupport UsOur Issues Social SecurityMedicareMedicaidOlder AmericansCoronavirusWhat We Do Take ActionLetters and Testimony2020Campaigns Hands Off No CutsDon’t Cut Pills Cut ProfitsBoost Social Security NowStop the War on the Working ClassBlogResources Delay and GainAsk Us116th CongressEleanor’s HopePACEqual TimeOur AlliesPollsReady to Attire
Search for:
Privacy
Home/Privacy
PrivacyNCPSSM2019-07-09T16:12:07-04:00
We value our members, donors and others who support the National Committee and its work by visiting our websites. We know that protecting personal information is important. This privacy policy applies to all the National Committee to Preserve Social Security and Medicare’s websites which include:
www.ncpssm.org
www.entitledtoknow.org
www.thetruthnow.org
www.eleanorshope.org
www.ncpssmfoundation.org
secure.ncpssm.org
www.handsoffmedicare.org
To make our Privacy Policy easy to find, we provide a link to it in the footer of every page of our site as well as in our emails.
What Information We Collect and How We Use That Information
Our registration forms require users to give us contact information that may include name, email address, message format preference (HTML vs. Text), address and other information. We retain contact information and preferences, but we do not retain or store sensitive financial information we receive from donors, such as credit card and bank account information. Credit card and bank information is never retained in our systems. In the following sections we explain in detail the types of data we collect, how we utilize it and your options in sharing your information.
We adhere to Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards (PCI DSS). This is a set of security standards designed to ensure that ALL companies that accept, process, store or transmit credit card information maintain a secure environment. To learn more information about this industry standard visit www.pcicomplianceguide.org/faq.
Security and Online Giving
All information provided to the National Committee is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt or scramble data before you send it to us. We also protect account information by placing it on a secure portion of our site that is only accessible to certain qualified employees of the National Committee. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. While we do our very best to protect your information, we cannot guarantee it.
When we receive a donation online, we also receive personal information and credit card information about the donor. The National Committee may also receive or collect and store a unique identification number associated with your device or your mobile application (including, for example, a unique device ID, Unique ID for Advertisers, Google Ad ID, or Windows Advertising ID), MAC address, mobile carrier, device type, model and manufacturer, mobile device operating system brand and model, and depending on your mobile device settings, your geographical location data, including GPS coordinates (e.g., latitude and longitude) or similar information regarding the location of your mobile device. This information is used in our website analysis and to ensure we provide the best user experience possible.
With constant development of new online tools, the National Committee reserves the right to amend without notice this Privacy Policy by posting such changes on this site. Changes will be effective immediately upon posting. We will post changes here, so please check back periodically. Changes will take effect when posted and your continued use of the site will constitute your agreement to the changes.
Internet Protocol (IP) Address
We collect an IP address from all visitors to our site. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP address information to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our site, analyze trends, track users’ movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the site and deliver customized, personalized content. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.
Analytics and Reporting
We use analytic and reporting technologies to record information such as Internet domain and host names, IP addresses, click stream patterns and the dates and times the National Committee website and services are accessed. We employ outside vendors who assist in managing, monitoring and optimizing our website to aid in measuring the effectiveness of our advocacy tools, advertising and the user experience on our site. For efficient analytics and reporting we may use tracking codes and cookies.
Use of “Cookies”
Our site may use cookies to enhance your experience while using our site. Cookies are pieces of information that some websites transfer to the computer that is browsing that website and are used for record-keeping purposes. Use of cookies makes web-surfing easier by performing certain functions such as saving your passwords, your personal preferences regarding your use of the particular website and to make sure you don’t see the same ads repeatedly. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard. Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the settings of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our site will not function properly when you view them.
Your Mailing Information and Opting Out
The National Committee rents and exchanges the names of its members in order to maintain a strong and effective membership base and to provide additional financial support for its work. If you do not wish to participate in this program or receive mailings from the National Committee, please let us know by calling (800) 966-1935 or by going to www.ncpssm.org/MailingPreferenceCenter.
Your Email Address and Opting Out of Email Lists
When signing up for email lists and alerts via the National Committee website, subscribers will receive periodic updates and action alerts by regular mail and email. You may opt out of receiving future information via email any time by using the unsubscribe procedure specified in the email message or by sending a message to: webmaster@ncpssm.org. The National Committee does not rent or exchange email addresses of its members and supporters.
Tell-A-Friend
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend’s name and email address. The National Committee will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. The National Committee stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.
Other Websites
Our site contains links to other websites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another website for which the National Committee has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on all such sites as their policies may be different than ours.
Social Media
We may share gathered information about you with various social media networks. This enables delivery of customized content and advertising about our advocacy efforts that you and others may find interesting. We provide this information confidentially to the social media platform so they can deliver proper advertising content to the correct user. Advertising preferences and opt out options are administered by the social media companies and privacy policies through which you receive the customized content. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of the social media sites with which you engage as they may differ from ours.
Information Collected by Third Parties
We may allow approved vendors to collect your personally identifiable information on our website, through our call center and other channels. They may use this information to perform services such as providing member services, sending mailings, improving advertising services and managing databases.
Take Action
If a user elects to participate in a National Committee call to action, your comments may also be shared with members of our social media communities, members of Congress and the Presidential Administration to lend your voice to our national campaign to preserve Social Security and Medicare.
Contacting the National Committee Website
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site or your transactions with this site, send them to webmaster@ncpssm.org.
National Committee to Preserve Social Security and Medicare
111 K Street, NE, Suite 700
Washington, DC 20002
800-966-1935
Subscribe to Email Alerts
111 K St. NE Suite 700
Washington DC 20002
ABOUT US
National Committee to Preserve Social Security and Medicare© Copyright 2020
Go to Top
